Colm Murphy

34 The Close, Coolroe Meadows, Ballincollig, P31DX09

Linkedin: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/iamcolm</u> **Web:** <u>www.iamcolm.com</u>

Profile

Experienced Product & UX Engineer with 5+ years working full time in enterprise design.

I have led design teams in native application design as well as desktop application and everything in between

A passionate experience engineer who likes to further a product's capabilities through design, accessibility and research.

I have developed and implemented personal Android applications as open source software, and enjoy contributing to technology communities as a means of education.

Design Skills

Prototyping: Figma, XD, Sketch.

Testing: Maze, Dovetail, Lookback

Handoff: Storybook, Zeplin.

Design: Adobe Creative Suite.

Technical Skills

Languages: Node.js, JavaScript & various JS Frameworks, HTML5, CSS & TailwindCSS,

Gulp/Grunt/Npm, Git.

Systems: Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Raspberry Pi.

Database: MySQL.

Career History

UX Lead Designer, The Access Group / People XD

January 2016 - Present 2022

- Lead the design team for the People Division which has multiple independent dev & design squads.
- Oversee the day to day product design and development of design toolkits, systems and processes for PeopleXD.
- Acts as an accessibility engineer for PeopleXD.
- Work cross divisionally with other design teams on the main access platform as a product designer and researcher.
- Acts as a consultant for Product teams and squads not usually in my working groups.

UX Designer, CoreHR

November 2016 - January 2020

- Redesigned the CoreHR desktop and Mobile experiences.
- Implemented Design Processes, Design Tool Kits and Systems.
- Eventually led the design team with responsibility for the day to day or direct reports.
- In House marketing graphic designer when required to assist with presentation, company events and social output.

UI/UX Designer, Teamwork.com

September 2015 - May 2016

- Conceived, designed and created the UI/UX interface for a suite of mobile applications.
- Solved and implemented design issues as part of both Android and iOS teams.
- Developed in Java android widgets and extensions of the primary app.

Technical Intern, Teamwork.com

March 2015 - September 2015

- Responsible as part of pair programming teams for the resolution and implementation of a product API in the golang programming language.
- Wrote and integrated responsive product web pages and landing pages.
- Acted as a software tester and customer support officer during the international product launch of teamwork desk, a customer and ticket support system.

Achievements

I consider myself a software enthusiast and have developed an Android Arabic & Hebrew application which is free and open source. I have also created personal web servers on Raspberry Pi hardware and software.

Guinness World Record holder

Education and Training

Computer Science BSc 2H2 September 2012 - May 2016

University College Cork

Computer Science FETAC Level 5 DistinctionSeptember 2011 - May 2012

Tralee Community College

Design For Print Distinction October 2010 - March 2011

Cork Institute Of Technology

Professional Memberships

Regular community contributor on UX Cork Meetup & Forums.

Interests

I have a strong interest in front-end creative development and community driven development as a means of learning and contributing. I am eager to implement the latest technologies to produce clean and efficient experiences..

I have a keen interest in the design of technology and am passionate about the process of usability driven design/development.

References available on request